Harvey Marshall

Huddersfield, West Yorkshire HD4 marshall.harvey@outlook.com 07397856238

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I currently work as a Data Engineer for PetsAtHome. I am predominantly working to build out a new Data Lakehouse utilising Microsoft Fabric to facilitate real-time analytics and Machine Learning Platforms. In My spare time I am partaking in the IBM AI Engineering Cerftification in a hope to transfer into an AI engineer role. My ability to adapt and learn is something I believe makes me stand out from the crowd. I have a very positive attitude and seek to create a good culture among all those I work with. One thing I have found in common with all my previous and current roles is that the best place to learn is from those around you. It is always better to ask questions and learn from those you work with. Among my strongest skills is my customer service. All the roles I have held have a strong emphasis on people; this has allowed me to solidify my people management and interaction skills. I am confident under pressure and have experience working towards deadlines and working within a fast-paced environment.

I am not afraid to ask questions and that is something that my current role requires of me on a daily basis. I believe that asking questions is a compulsory skill for any job. It's better to ask a question than struggle with no answer or guidance.

A big thing for me and my workplace is the culture. I want to work somewhere that puts the people, whether that is customers or employees at the forefront of everything they do.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer

Pets at Home - Manchester, Greater Manchester | November 2024 to Present

I work within the MLOps squad at pets to build out a new Data Lakehouse platform using new Microsoft Fabric tooling, this platform will be used to facilitate Operational analytics and Machine Learning Platforms. I am also looking at ways we can utilise AI within our workflow using AI agents to increase productivity. I also work within the Analytics Platform and Data Engineering team at Pets At Home. Where the past few months I have been the single colleague working on designing solutions to ingest data from varying sources into our Data lake on the Google Cloud Platform. The main subject of my work has been to integrate Azure Event services such as Service Bus and Event Hub. I have also created a custom application allowing non-technical users to generate Apache airflow pipelines just using YAML files. Alongside other work I have used docker containers to build code used within apache airflow to ingest and sink various data to a variety of sources and destinations. I also helped to build and manage a system for deploying dbt models within this new DAG infrastructure and used the DBT tooling to help build out our data lake using BigQuery External tables defined on top of Google Cloud Storage buckets. As part of this I completed the DBT fundamentals course to ensure my skills in DBT were adequate.

Lead Data Engineer

N Brown Group - Manchester | July 2024 to September 2024

I worked as a Lead Data Engineer helping to shape and form the new analytics platform for use throughout the business. This has included a review of how Google Cloud Platform infrastructure is managed and used as well as IAM policies. I have also began work to reimagine the data ingestion processes used within the business to help improve and shape the best ways of working so data is made available to the business in an efficient and structured manner. Alongside this work I have also been skilling up on the use of DBT for data transformation particularly in the use of creating and managing temporal data tables within Google BigQuery.

Data Engineer

Pets at Home - Manchester | November 2021 to June 2024

I worked within the Analytics Platform and Data Engineering team at Pets At Home. Where the past few months I have been the single colleague working on designing solutions to ingest data from varying sources into our Data lake on the Google Cloud Platform. The main subject of my work has been to integrate Azure Event services such as Service Bus and Event Hub. I have also created a custom application allowing non-technical users to generate Apache airflow pipelines just using YAML files. Alongside other work I have used docker containers to build code used within apache airflow to ingest and sink various data to a variety of sources and destinations. I also helped to build and manage a system for deploying dbt models within this new DAG infrastructure and used the DBT tooling to help build out our data lake using BigQuery External tables defined on top of Google Cloud Storage buckets. As part of this I completed the DBT fundamentals course to ensure my skills in DBT were adequate.

Data Engineer/Operations and Analytics Engineer

Betway Group - London | May 2021 to October 2021

I work within a small team that is responsible for the movement, organisation and analysing of live data across many different sources. We use tools such as elastic search, kibana and log stash to move and analyse data as well as alert on specific use cases in line with the many responsible gambling laws and stipulations in place for our company. I personally have also used my python skills heavily to create azure functions used to gather data and transform it from sources such as APIs and Databases. I hope to increase my learning here and get more experience with the Microsoft azure tools and concepts. Working with Azure I have managed to develop some knowledge and skills using infrastructure as code tools such as Terraform. I also work with visualisations using the kibana tool to create dashboards displaying meaningful data to stakeholders.

Business Analyst/Junior Data Engineer

Covea Insurance - Halifax | June 2018 to May 2021

Currently I work within a team building out the new data platform or data ecosystem. This involves gathering requirements on capabilities and needs for the data platform such as Data Ingestion, Storage/Retention, Data Transformation etc. I also help to define the asks and problems of stakeholders who may require access to new data or the ingestion of valuable data sets. While also fulfilling my Business Analyst Responsibilities I have also been skilling up to take on data engineering tasks. I have learnt skills such as Python and SQL as well as how to work with technology such as Apache Kafka, AWS and Confluent Cloud. I hope to continue honing these skills and learn as much as I can to hopefully progress to a full time Data Engineering role.

Lane Host

Hollywood Bowl - Leeds, UK | February 2018 to May 2018

When at university I gained part time employment as a Lane host at the Hollywood bowl. This role involved serving customer drinks, handling money and dealing with customer requests and questions. I had to leave this position when I made the decision to move back home and leave university due to health issues.

Social Media Manager and General Assistant

Opus Photografix - Bradford, UK | March 2017 to June 2017

I began an apprenticeship with Opus Photografix as a social media and marketing executive. My role their included creating leads as well as helping the design team with creation of content for the social media channels which I also took responsibility for. Unfortunately, this was a short-term position but I really enjoyed the glimpse into a tech driven career which I knew from then I would enjoy. During my short time there I had a glimpse of the future role I would love to have within a more appropriate company.

Food and Beverage Assistant

Holiday Inn - Brighouse, UK | November 2016 to March 2017

I was a food and beverage team member I learnt great communication skills at this due to working closely with my team. This job included many responsibilities many of which were customer facing. I always worked within my best ability to create the best experience for the customer and hotel guests. I had to leave this job as I moved to university.

Bar Staff

Brighouse Sports Club - Brighouse, UK | December 2014 to September 2016

I firstly started working as a Bar back collecting glasses, restocking shelves and keeping the bar clean. After creating more trust with my employer, I was moved to the position of Bartender where I was responsible for making drinks and taking cash from customers as well as using the till system correctly. Then I was trusted to do solo shifts during the week which involved opening and closing the bar by myself.

EDUCATION

Leeds Beckett University

Leeds, UK | September 2017 to May 2018

A Levels in Law

Brighouse Sixth Form College - Brighouse, UK | September 2015 to July 2017

GCSE

Brighouse High School - Brighouse, UK | September 2010 to July 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

SQL

Apache Airflow (2 years)

Google Cloud Platform (2 years)

Azure Cloud Platform

AWS

DBT (1 year)

Go (2 years)

Kafka

Terraform

CI/CD (2 years)

Git

React Native (Less than 1 year)

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

DBT Fundamentals Course

June 2024 to Present